import Puzzle from "../models/puzzle";

export const puzzlesEN: Array<Puzzle> = [
  {
    question: "How many member states are in the United Nations (UN)? (rounded)",
    answer: 190
  },
  {
    question: "What's the population of the United States? (rounded)",
    answer: 330_000_000,
    hint: 'In 1990 it was about 250 million.',
  },
  {
    question: "How many people have died of COVID-19, worldwide? (rounded)",
    answer: 6_800_000
  },
  {
    question: "What's the median age in Africa?",
    answer: 19
  },
  { // 2022-07-29
    question: "What is the 2023 estimated GDP (gross domestic product) of China, in billion U.S. dollars? (rounded)",
    answer: 19_000,
    hint: "United States' 2023 estimated GDP is 26,000 billion U.S. dollars."
  },
  {
    question: "How many McDonald's restaurants are there in the United States? (rounded)",
    answer: 13_000
  },
  {
    question: "What percent of the Earth's surface is convered by water?",
    answer: 70
  },
  {
    question: "What's the population of New York? (rounded)",
    answer: 8_800_000,
    hint: "The population of Los Angeles is about 3,800,000 people."
  },
  {
    question: "How many passengers can Wonder of the Seas, the largest cruise ship in the world, carry? (rounded)",
    answer: 6_900,
    hint: 'The Titanic could carry 2,400 passengers.'
  },
  { // 2022-08-05
    question: "How many drivers compete for the Formula 1 World Championship?",
    answer: 20
  },
  {
    question: "What percent of the U.S. population is Christian?",
    answer: 63,
  },
  {
    question: "What's the distance on road between New York and Washington DC, in miles? (rounded)",
    answer: 220
  },
  { // 2022-08-12
    question: "How many states are in the US?",
    answer: 50
  },
  {
    question: "What percent of the votes went in 2020 to Joe Biden?",
    answer: 51
  },
  {
    question: "What's the population of Los Angeles? (rounded)",
    answer: 3_800_000,
    hint: "The population of New York is about 8,800,000 people."
  },
  {
    question: "How many U.S. bank holidays are in 2023?",
    answer: 13
  },
  {
    question: "How many people died in the September 11, 2011 attacks in the U.S.? (rounded)",
    answer: 2_900
  },
  { // 2022-08-19
    question: "How many countries are in South America?",
    answer: 12
  },
  {
    question: "How many years passed between World War I and World War II?",
    answer: 20
  },
  {
    question: "How many chemical elements are now in the periodic table? (rounded)",
    answer: 110
  },
  {
    question: "What's the population of Mexico? (rounded)",
    answer: 120_000_000
  },
  {
    question: "How long is the Nile, the longest river in the world, in miles? (rounded)",
    answer: 4_100,
    hint: "Mississippi, the fourth longest, is about 3,900 miles long."
  },
  { // 2022-08-26
    question: "What's the speed of light, in miles per second? (rounded)",
    answer: 180_000
  },
  {
    question: "How many number-one singles in the US did Michael Jackson have?",
    answer: 13
  },
  {
    question: "How many players are in a rugby team?",
    answer: 15
  },
]
